Jensen, Eric F. Labor Negotiation files 6177
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Eric F. Jensen Labor Negotiation files
1959-1981
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Jensen, Eric F.
6177
2 cubic feet
2 linear ft.
Records.
5830495
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, July 10, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 24, 2016
Biographical / Historical
Eric F. Jensen has been active in the field of industrial relations as an attorney and corporate executive for over twenty-five years.
Starting with ACF Industries as Assistant Manager, Labor Relations in early 1961, he became Manager, Labor Relations by the end of that year and Director - Industrial Relations in 1964. He was elected Vice President - Industrial Relations in August 1965 and Vice President - Government and Labor Relations in 1979.
Mr. Jensen was with Bethlehem Steel Company for ten years prior to joining ACF, holding various positions in production and industrial relations in one of their shipyards in New York from 1951 to 1956 before becoming an Arbitration Attorney in Bethlehem's corporate office.
As Vice President - Industrial Relations for ACF, Mr. Jensen was responsible for all employee relations policies, programs and activities throughout the company including compensation, community relations, employee benefits, labor relations, management development and training, safety and health, and security.
In his current position, he is responsible for the company's government relations activities and programs while continuing his former responsibilities for community relations, labor relations, safety and health, security, and wage and incentive administration.
He is a native of New York City, born in 1927. He graduated from Cornell University in 1951 with a BS degree in industrial and labor relations. He earned his JD from Brooklyn Law School and admittance to the New York Bar in 1956. In 1968, he attended the Advanced Management Program at Harvard.
Jensen was Chariman of the Advisory Council of the Industrial and Labor Relations School at Cornell for eight years and is now Chairman of the Human Resources Advisory Council for the University. In 1971 he received the first annual Judge William B. Groat award from the I&LR school for his contributions in the field of industrial relations.
He is a member of the US Department of Labor Federal Committee on Apprenticeship; Nova University Advisory Board - Center for Study of Administration; Education, Employment and Training Committee of the Chamber of commerce of the United States; The Public Affairs Steering Committee and Chairman of the Labor Relations Steering Group of the National Association of Manufacturers; member of the Board of Trustees of the National Center on Occupational Readjustment, Inc.; Human Resources and Public Affairs Councils of the Machinery and Allied Products Institute; Legislative Affairs Committee of the Railway Progress Institute; Labor Relations and Administrative Law Sections of the American Bar Association; Labor Policy Association; Industrial Relations Research Association; director and pas president of the Industrial Relations Society and; New York Industrial Relations Association.
Biographical / Historical
ACF Industries leases a fleet of tank and hopper railroad cars to industrial users and railroads. The company also manufactures railroad cars and parts; carburetors, fuel pumps and other automotive fuel system components; valves and controls for petroleum, gas and other industrial uses; and industrial plastic shapes, sheets and powders, through its subsidiary The Polymer Corporation.
ACF is headquartered in New York City.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Jensen, Eric F.
5830495
- Minutes of Meetings ACF/SCL USOA 1959/1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 1962 ACF/SL USOA Minutes of Meetings (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 1962 ACF/SL USOA minutes of meetings folder2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 1965 Steelworker Negotiations ACF and SL (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 1965 Steelworkers Negotiations ACF and SL folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- 1965 Steelworker Negotiation ACF and SL (Box 1, Folder 6)
- 1969 USWA Negotiations Minutes of Meetings Vol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- 1969 USWA Negotiations Minutes of Meeting Vol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- 1969 USWA Negotiations Minutes of Meetings Vol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- 1969 USWA Negotiations Vol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- 1969 USWA Negotiations Vol. 2 folder 2 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 1969 USWA Negotiations Vol. 2 folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- 1972 ACF Negotiations with United Steelworkers - minutes of meetings (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 1972 ACF Negotiations with United Steelworkers of (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1972 ACF Negotiations with United Steelworkers - minutes of meeting folder 3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- 1975 Steelworker Negotiations - minutes (Box 2, Folder 1)
- 1975 Steelworker Negotiations - Minutes (Box 2, Folder 2)
- 1975 Shippers Negotiations - minutes (Box 2, Folder 3)
- 1975 Shippers Steelworker Agreements (Box 2, Folder 4)
- 1975 AMCAR Steelworker Agreements (Box 2, Folder 5)
- 1975 AMCAR Steelworker Agreements (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 1980 Carter Carburetor and UAW (Box 2, Folder 7)
- 1981 Negotiations -Carter Carburetor and UAW folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- 1981 Negotiations -Carter Carburetor and UAW folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- 1981 USW Minutes of Meetings vo. 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- 1981 USW Minutes of Meetings vol. 1 folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- 1981 USE Minutes of Meetings vol. 1 folder 3 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 1981 USW Minutes of Meetings vol. 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- 1981 USW Negotiations vol. 2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- 1981 USW Negotiations Vol. 2 folder 2 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- 1981 USW Negotiations UAW Vol. 2 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- 1981 USW Negotiations Vol. 2 (Box 2, Folder 17)